[
    {
        "question": "In which European city can you find the `Mouth of Truth`?",
        "answer": "Rome"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country would you find the world`s oldest golf course?",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the letters in USSR stand for?",
        "answer": "Union of Soviet Socialist Republics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state`s name begins but doesn`t end with the letter A?",
        "answer": "Arkansas"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many US states end with the letter `O`?",
        "answer": "Four"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US states end with the letter `O`?",
        "answer": "Colorado, Idaho, New Mexico and Ohio"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where in London are the Crown Jewels kept?",
        "answer": "The Tower of London"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Ireland?",
        "answer": "Dublin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was renamed to Ho Chi Minh City in 1975?",
        "answer": "Saigon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country lies directly south of Detroit?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest Scandinavian country?",
        "answer": "Sweden"
    },
    {
        "question": "What continent is Jamaica considered part of?",
        "answer": "North America"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state has the highest relative humidity?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "What mode of transportation is Missouri named for?",
        "answer": "Canoe (An Illinois tribe`s phrase for the area`s people, `ouemessourita,` translates to \u201cwooden canoe people`.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state gets its name from a made-up word?",
        "answer": "Idaho (Mining lobbyist George M. Willing told Congress `Idaho` was a Native American phrase for `gem of the mountains`. He made it up.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does Texas` original name mean?",
        "answer": "Friends"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the state motto for the U.S. state Texas?",
        "answer": "`Friendship`"
    },
    {
        "question": "The San Blas Islands are part of which Central American nation?",
        "answer": "Panama"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which building houses the world`s biggest four-faced chiming clock?",
        "answer": "Minneapolis City Hall"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which river does the Brooklyn Bridge cross?",
        "answer": "East River"
    },
    {
        "question": "The US state of California was originally part of which Spanish territorial colony?",
        "answer": "New Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is the third largest state by land area?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which harbour is the Sydney Opera House located?",
        "answer": "Sydney Harbour"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the World`s largest landlocked country by land area?",
        "answer": "Kazakhstan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What marks the border between Asia and Africa?",
        "answer": "Suez Canal"
    },
    {
        "question": "The `Khyber Pass` connects what two countries?",
        "answer": "Afghanistan and Pakistan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to the Valley of Fire?",
        "answer": "Nevada"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bibimbap is a traditional rice dish from which region?",
        "answer": "Korea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What U.S. city is known for its hot chicken?",
        "answer": "Nashville"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Semper Opera House is located where?",
        "answer": "Dresden, Germany"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through Cairo?",
        "answer": "Nile"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through Rome?",
        "answer": "Tiber"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through Boston?",
        "answer": "Charles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through Baghdad?",
        "answer": "Tigris"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through St. Petersburg?",
        "answer": "Neva"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through Cleveland?",
        "answer": "Cuyahoga"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Scandinavian nation has a yellow cross on its flag?",
        "answer": "Sweden"
    },
    {
        "question": "What popular tourist destination is Thailand`s largest island?",
        "answer": "Phuket"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who christened Hawaii `the Sandwich Islands` in 1778?",
        "answer": "Captain Cook"
    },
    {
        "question": "What California region includes Alameda and Contra Costa counties?",
        "answer": "East Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Washington, D.C. street is often used as shorthand for the lobbying industry?",
        "answer": "K"
    },
    {
        "question": "Chablis is the northernmost district of what French wine region?",
        "answer": "Burgundy"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which continent would you find the river Nile?",
        "answer": "Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Canadian city was originally called Bytown?",
        "answer": "Ottawa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Canadian city`s nickname is `Bytown`?",
        "answer": "Ottawa"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Easter lily is a native plant of which country?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Easter lily is a plant endemic to which Japanese islands?",
        "answer": "Ryukyu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the Australia`s Northern Territory?",
        "answer": "Darwin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Pitcairn Islands?",
        "answer": "Adamstown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the nickname for Rome, Italy?",
        "answer": "Eternal City"
    }
]